Curriculum Vitae Jaroslav Zajonc

1. February 1973 Gouda, Netherlands Tel.: +31(0)639 719 767

E-mail: jaro@zajonc.nl

Summary

A versatile professional engineer with 20 years of experience in developing IT solutions. Good understating of modern programming languages and integration of different computer systems. Knowledge of IT operation, automation, high availability, UNIX/Linux systems. Experience working in International environment. Professional, creative, flexible, fast learner.

Employment

11/2017 – present UNHCR (UN Refugee Agency)

UNHCR Kenya (remote homebased)

Senior Software Developer

Job description

Design, development and integration of KASI (Kiosk Automated Services and Information) innovation tool. Employed CI/CD techniques to speed up the development cycle. Using docker containerization, solution is deployed as a combination of on premise and cloud based (AWS) services.

Following modules were developed:

KASI backend: an Odoo CRM based application. It serves as a backend management system. Built as an Odoo CRM module, using Python. It provides services such as resource management, bulk SMS interface for mass communication with Persons of Interest, appointments scheduling logic or users enrolment features.

KASI kiosk: a frontend web-based application serving as a Kiosk, located at various locations within the Refugee Camp. It enables Persons of Interest to review their personal data and schedule the appointments with UNHCR staff. After the enrolment into the system, Refugees need to authenticate themselves by means of 2-factor SMS authentication. Kiosk application is build using JavaScript on top of opensource ReactJS framework. It offers also a localization to multiple languages with possibility of adding new languages if required.

KASI middleware: This component offers an abstraction layer, using GraphQL. It is a NodeJS based JavaScript application. As a middleware component, it serves also as API gateway, providing integration with proGres (UNHCR proprietary MS Dynamics CRM platform) and additional MS SQL based databases to retrieve required data in real time. Middleware also interact with Odoo backend application using XML-RPC based interface.

It is also providing SMS Gateway integration and implements SMS queuing and retry mechanism if 3rd party SMS gateway isn't responsive.

Finally, authentication and authorization layers are implemented here.

08/2013 - 10/2017 F5 Networks

Schiphol, NL

Type of business

Technology, Telecom

Position

Consultant Professional Services, Diameter Signaling

Job description

Delivering F5 SDC product portfolio across whole EMEA region. Working closely with customer engineering departments, defining solution architecture, IP planning, Connectivity matrix. Writing High

Level, Low Level design documents.

IT automation

Deploying customized solutions fitting customer's needs reflecting agreed design decisions. Extensive use of automation/orchestration

tools such as SaltStack and Ansible.

Scrips development

Developing rather complex scripts on the application level, in order to cope with customer specific use cases and signaling flows.

08/2007 - 08/2013

Sotersat BV

Leiden, NL

Solution Architect

Job description

Developing full scaled GPS tracking system for fleet management which includes data acquisition, database design, GIS systems integration, API development, 3rd party API integration, user interface and mobile app development.

Backend services:

Designed and developed backend client/server based services to integrate with 3rd party vendors proprietary protocols and interfaces, employing Event-Loop based programing techniques. Developed own reverse-geocoding service employing position geohashing and in-memory cache (Redis) in order to optimize response speeds.

Developed proprietary SMS notification and premium-sms services. Developed Parking-bot, automatic parking activation/deactivation service integrating with external parking provider and employing BigData techniques (RDW data scraping, MongDB) to match vehicle location against open parking zones data.

User interface

Developed user facing frontend web application including real-time web-socket services, using Perl/Catalyst and Mojolicious web frameworks.

Designed and Developed Iphone app including deployment of own push notification service platform.

API development

Designed and developed proprietary API interface to enable 3rd party applications integration into the Sotersat environment. Integrated with 3rd party API services such as Yellowbrick parking service and RDW open data services.

Odoo integration

Designed and participated in Odoo CRM module development to integrate with Sotersat platform. Developing related API as well as custom views to enable Vehicle location visibility in Odoo environment.

07/2010 - 07/2013

T-Mobile Nederland BV

Waldorpstraat 60, Den Haag, NL

Type of business

Mobile Operator, Telecom

Position System Expert VAS & VOICE

Job description FMC (Fix mobile convergence VOIP solution) implementation

> project. Performing system integration, defining system provisioning flows with respect to company overall Tibco provisioning chain. Managing Value Added Services such as SMSc, Intelligent Network

systems and FMC (VOIP based) systems.

Designed in implemented web based monitoring tool for billing data extracted from Broadwoks FMC platform. Tool provided valuable information on current overall traffic as well as its distribution over customer base. Statistical views on success rates and errors

distribution.

07/2007 - 06/2010 **ERICSSON Telecommunicate BV**

Ericssonstraat 2, Rijen, NL

Type of business **Position**

Telecom vendor and managed services provider

Support Services Engineer

BackOffice Multimedia Messaging and Provisioning solutions

Job description Managing complex Provisioning, Subscriber, Number Management

and Mediation chains and systems.

Responsible for support, provisioning and management of E/// IMS (VOIP) and VAS solutions deployed over various customers in NL, BE

and UK.

Developed set of tools for KPI monitoring and reporting over various

customers within Ericsson IMS deployment.

04/2000 - 06/2007 Orange Nederland N.V

Groenhovenstraat 2, Den Haag, NL

Mobile operator, Telecom

Type of business

Position Senior BSS support engineer

Job description Providing 2nd level support for radio part of GSM, GPRS, UMTS

networks.

Developed several tools to simplify day to day operation of Radio

network.

Management, testing and implementation of new system releases. Responsible for configuration management of the radio network, implementation of frequency plans, parameter changes, new

equipments integration.

Tools development towards proprietary system interfaces such as Q3, ASN.1 and development of web based front end user interfaces

using Perl, C/C++, CGI-perl.

12/1996 - 03/2000 Globtel Slovensko a.s.

Plynarenska 1, Bratislava, Slovak republic

Type of business

Position

Mobile operator, Telecom BSS support engineer

Job description BSS system and applications management.

Education

1991 - 1996 Technical University, L. Mikulas, Slovak Republic

Telecommunication Faculty - 5 years study

Main subject Telecommunication systems

Degree obtained Dipl-Ing. (MSc.)

Final state exams 1. Telecommunication systems 2. Transmission systems

3. Telecommunication management systems

Final dissertation Modeling of data signal using ATM cells (developed using Borland

DEPLHI)

1988 - 1991 Gymnasium Kezmarok, Slovak Republic

Other Education & Training & Certifications

Certifications ITIL V3, PRINCE2, F5 101 - Application Delivery Fundamentals, 201 - TMOS Administration, Cisco CCNA Routing and Switching

Other Skills

Telco: Diameter, S6A, Gx, Gy, FMC, VOIP, SIP, Trunking, TCP/IP, SS7,

SIGTRAN, BSSAP, MAP, ISUP, CAMEL CAP, VAS, SMSc, MMSc, UCP,

SMPP, CIMD, IN, Broadworks, SBC, CDR, Billing,

IT: Linux (CentOS, RHEL, Ubuntu), UNIX (Solaris), OPEN VMS, MAC OS,

XML, JSON, SOAP, LDAP, O&M, REST, HTTP, VmWare ESXi, KVM,

SaltStack, Ansible, Docker, AWS

Databases: SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Cassandra, Redis, Sybase, Oracle

Programming: Perl, Python, Shell (Bash, Sh) scripting, C/C++, SVN, CVS, Git, Apache,

Tomcat, Catalyst, Mojolicious, DBIx, Javascript – Node.js, Groovy.

Languages: Slovak – Native

	<u>Speak</u>	Read	Write
Czech	Good	Fluent	Fluent
English	Good	Good	Good
Dutch	Fair	Good	Fair